（男の子）《椿が風邪！？》
Tsubaki caught a cold?!
（男の子）
《年中　半ズボンの女ゴリラが！？》
That she-gorilla who wears shorts year-round?
（女の子）《変なくしゃみ》
What a weird sneeze.
（渡）《バイオハザード…》
（男の子）《衛生兵！》
Bio-hazard incoming.
Call the combat medics!
Take shelter!
（男の子）《待避！》
（男の子）《ゴリチヌス菌だ！》
Gorilla germs!
Huh?
Who you callin' a gorilla?!
（椿）《誰がゴリラじゃー！》
（男の子）《マウンティングだ！》
Huh?
It's on the warpath!
（公生）《はい　レモネード》
（椿）《うっ　何よ　それ？》
n
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
a
d
e
n
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
e
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
e
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
e
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
e
Here, some lemonade.
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
e
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
e
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
e
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
e
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
e
Wh-What's up with that?
My mom said that vitamin C's good for colds.
《風邪にはビタミンＣがいいって
お母さんが言ってたよ》
（椿）《べ…　別に風邪ひいてないしゴリラ　風邪ひかないし》
I-It's not like I have a cold!
Gorillas don't catch colds anyway...
《椿はゴリラじゃないよ》
You're not a gorilla.
（公生）《椿は　女の子だよ》
You're a girl, Tsubaki.
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
e
（椿）《治ったー！》
《おおっ！》
All better now!
Whoa...
Happy New Year!
Man, entrance exams are here.
（生徒）あ～　受験だ。
（生徒）冬休み　講習漬けだよ。
I was cramming all through winter break.
Maybe I should try for a lower-ranked school.
（生徒）
志望校のランク落とそうかな。
Long time no see!
（生徒）久しぶり。
（生徒）推薦　決まったって。
He got early admission.
（生徒）えっ　ずりぃ。
（椿）フフフ…。
No fair!
Wednesday, January 11th
Daily Duty: Yoshioka Akae
（椿）Ｂ判定きたー！
I scored a B!
（柏木）愛ね。
（生徒）愛だね。
She's lovestruck.
Yeah, she's lovestruck.
（生徒）愛ゆえに。
（椿）オッホホ…　うあっ。
Truly the power of love.
（椿）
やればできるんだから　椿ちゃん。
You can do it if you try, Tsubaki!
ヘヘヘ…　自慢してやろ。
I'm gonna go brag to him!
Music Preparation Room
公生ー。　あっ…。
Kousei!
Darn.
Hey!
Where do you think you're going?
どこ行くんだよ。
（公生）嫌だよ。　邪魔になるだけだ。
No way! I'll only be a third wheel!
STOP
You're checking in, right?
（渡）定期連絡だろ。
俺のかをりちゃんが待ってるって。
My Kaori's waiting.
Medication Room
（渡）あけおめ。
Happy New Year!
（かをり）あけおめ。　うんっ？
Medication Room
てめえ　予選　通ったからって→
Just because you made it through the prelims, don't get too ahead of yourself and slack off!
調子ぶっこいて　こんな所で
油　売ってんじゃねーよ！
練習しろ　カスが！
Go practice, you loser!
You're the one who told me to stop by!
《あんたが来いって
言ったんでしょうが》
（渡）今日　学校でさー。
うん　うん。
Y'know, today at school...
Yeah?
（渡）女子高に行くって言った子が
いたんだけど→
This one girl said she's going to an all-girls school.
女子高って
やっぱ華やかなのかな？
I guess all-girls schools are kind of glamorous, huh?
アハハ　どうだろう？
I dunno about that.
（渡）かをりちゃんは　すっごく
似合いそうだね。　女子高。
You'd fit right in at an all-girls school!
Really? You think so?
え～　そうかな？
（渡）うん　うん　うん。
Definitely!
（椿）
《かをちゃんは　渡が好きなの》
Kao likes Watari.
《渡君　渡君》
Watari!
友達を好きな　女の子。
The girl who likes my best friend.
僕は　盗撮魔で　代役で
荷物持ちで→
I've been a voyeur, and a substitute, and a baggage handler,
ピアニストで　伴奏者で
僕は　渡じゃない。
and a pianist, and an accompanist...
But... I'm not Watari.
《ねえ　本気？》
Hey, are you serious?
（椿）《公生ママ　激おこだよ》
Your mom's gonna get really mad.
《飼ってもらえるように
頑張って　お願いしてみる》
If I ask her a lot of times, I bet she'll let me keep her.
My mom likes animals too, you know?
《お母さんだって
動物好きなんだ》
《きっと　大丈夫》
I'm sure she'll let me.
（泣き声）
（椿）《飲んで》→
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
Drink this.
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
《早く　体　拭かないと
風邪　ひいちゃうよ》
If you don't dry yourself off, you'll catch a cold!
I couldn't find Chelsea anywhere.
《チェルシー　どこにもいなかったゴミ捨て場にも　橋の下にも》
Not at the junkyard or under the bridge...
《こんな寒いのに　外にいたら
死んじゃうよ》
If she's out here in this cold, she'll die!
《僕　何も言えなくて→
Even though I knew that my mom was going to get rid of her, I couldn't say a word.
お母さんが捨てに行くの
分かってたのに→
チェルシーは
生きていれたかもしれないのに》
Chelsea might be still alive and out there!
（女性）《操り人形》
（男性）《ヒューマンメトロノーム》
A puppet.
The human metronome.
《みんなの言うとおりだ》
They're exactly right.
《僕は　お母さんがつくった
心のない人形なんだ》
I'm just a heartless puppet that my mother created.
《そんなことない
公生には心があるよ》
That's not true.
You do have a heart.
《いいとこ　いっぱい
いっぱいあるよ》
There are tons and tons of good things about you!
《私　知ってるもん。　例えば…》
I know you do!
Like...
You're running around for her like your life depended on it.
（椿）《今だって　一生懸命
走り回ってる》→
《それは
後悔してるからでしょ》→
Isn't that because you regret it?
《チェルシーに　ごめんなさい
したいからでしょ》→
You want to tell Chelsea you're sorry, right?
《公生には　ちゃんと心がある》→
You do have a heart, Kousei.
《ただ
隠すのが上手になっただけ》→
It's just that you're so good at hiding it...
《自分でも
見つけられないくらいに》
that even you can't find it.
《だから　私が見つけてあげる》
So I'm going to find it for you.
《迷わないように
後悔しないように→
I promise to stay by your side forever
ずっとそばにいてあげる》
so you won't lose your way or have regrets.
《公生のことなんて
何でも知ってるんだから》
After all, I know everything about you, Kousei.
Visiting the hospital today?
（椿）今日は　病院？
（公生）うん。
Yeah.
定期連絡って呼び出しといて→
She orders me to check in with her regularly,
but then she tells me to practice if I have the time to go.
来る暇あったら練習しろ
って言うんだ。　矛盾だよ。
Which one is it?
STOP
Tokyo Metropolitan regulations
require all car engines to be
turned off while the car is parked.
STOP
渡。
Watari...
Tokyo Metropolitan regulations
require all car engines to be
turned off while the car is parked.
Tokyo Metropolitan regulations
require all car engines to be
turned off while the car is parked.
He came to see Kao too?
渡も
かをちゃんのお見舞いに来たんだ。
椿。　雨が来そうだよ。
今日は　帰ろっか。
Tsubaki,
it looks like it's gonna rain.
Let's head home today instead.
I can smell the rain.
（椿）《雨の匂いがする》
あっ…。
あ～　来たよ。　降ってきた。
Wow, it's starting to pour really hard.
H
o
t
L
e
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
e
o
n
a
d
e
a
n
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
d
e
H
o
t
L
e
m
o
n
a
H
o
t
L
e
はい。
あっ　サンキュー。
Here.
Thanks.
どうせなら　雪の方がいいな。
I wish it would just snow instead.
いいなって思うのは
積もるまでだよ。
You'll take that back when it piles up.
（椿）雪に味がついてたら
世界は平和だよね。
If the snow had its own flavor, we'd have world peace, huh?
If our tap water was lemonade,
it would eradicate the common cold.
水道水がレモネードだったら
風邪は絶滅だ。
（椿）《いつもの会話。
じゃれ合うような冗談》→
Talking like we always do.
The banter and joking around.
《突然の雨宿り》
Having to take shelter from the sudden rain.
椿　カワイイ　ハンカチ使ってるね。
That's a cute handkerchief you're using, Tsubaki.
（椿）《隣には　男の子》
A boy right next to me.
椿は女の子みたいだ。
You're like a girl, Tsubaki.
You're a girl, Tsubaki.
《椿は　女の子だよ》
《椿は女の子なんだな》
So you are a girl after all!
（椿）《嘘つき》
Liar.
（椿）嫌だったんでしょ
かをちゃんのとこ行くの。→
I know you didn't want to go see Kao.
渡がいたから。
あっ…。
Because Watari was there.
そんなんじゃないよ。
That's not it.
（椿）嘘つき。
Liar.
だってさ　邪魔しちゃ悪いだろ。
せっかく２人でいるのに。
Well, I didn't think we should get in their way,
especially when it could just be the two of them.
No!
違うよ！　公生は嫌なんだ！
You just can't take it!
かをちゃんと渡が　笑ってるのが
見てるのが　つらいんだ。
It hurts to see Kao and Watari laughing together.
（椿）《だから　避けるんだ》
That's why you're avoiding her.
《椿の我慢なんか　すぐ分かる》
I can tell right away when you're holding back.
（椿）《君が私のそばにいたように
私は　君のそばにいたんだよ》→
Just like you stayed by my side, I stayed by yours.
《公生のことなんか　すぐ分かる》
If it's about you, I'll notice right away.
公生は
かをちゃんが好きなんだよ。
You like Kao, Kousei.
（椿）《美和が言ってたよ》→
I was talking to Miwa the other day.
《彼と出会った瞬間
私の人生が変わったの》→
"The moment I met him,
my life changed.
《見るもの　聞くもの　感じるもの
私の風景　全部が→
Everything I saw, everything I heard, everything I felt...
The world around me was suddenly saturated in color.
カラフルに色付き始めたの。
世界が輝きだしたの》
As if everything had just started to sparkle."
《友人Ａ》
Friend A!
Yeah.
バッカじゃないの！
かをちゃんは　渡が好きなんだよ！
What a moron!
Kao likes Watari, you know!
ずっとそうだったじゃん！→
She always did, remember?
As if she'd ever give you a second look!
あんたが
相手にされるはずないじゃん！
知ってる。
I know.
（椿）女の子関係で　渡が相手なら
１ｍｍも勝ち目なんかないんだよ！
You won't stand a single chance if
you're up against Watari, you know!
知ってる。
I know.
（椿）《嘘つき》→
Liar.
《そばにいるって言ったくせに》
You said you'd stay by my side.
《椿の我慢なんか　すぐ分かる》
I can tell right away when you're holding back.
（椿）《私のこと
何も知らないくせに》→
You don't know the first thing about me,
《嘘つき。　私を女の子だなんて
思ったこともないくせに》
you liar.
You've never once thought of me as a girl.
バッカじゃないの。
What a moron...
かをちゃんは　渡が好きなの。
Kao likes Watari.
あんたは…。→
And you...
私と恋するしかないの。
have no choice but to love me!
あー！
（椿）バーカ　バーカ！
Moron! Moron!
（椿）《どうだ　思い知ったか
ざまあ見ろ》→
How's that for taking the plunge? Screw you!
《踏みだしてやったぞ》→
I took the first step!
《女の子として
意識させてやったぞ》→
I made him see me as a girl!
《私は　いっぱい苦しんだんだ》→
I went through a lot of suffering.
《あんたも　苦しめ。
苦しんで　苦しんで→
So you can suffer too!
Suffer and suffer, and think about me constantly!
私のこと　いっぱい考えろ》→
《やっと　始まったんだ》→
It finally started.
《でも
どうなっちゃうんだろう》→
But what's gonna happen now?
《心臓が飛び出そう。
冬の雨が気持ちいい》→
My heart's about to burst.
The rain in winter feels so good.
《レモネードの味がする》→
It tastes like lemonade.
《私の時間は
動きだしたばかりだ》
The time I exist in...
Your Lie in April
just started flowing.
あっ…。　おはよう。
M-Morning...
あっ。
（柏木）おい。　椿。
Hey, Tsubaki!
I'm exhausted. Let's go home.
（柏木）もう疲れた。　帰ろう。
風邪気味なんだろ？
Don't you have a cold?
I just got caught in the rain.
雨にあたっただけ。
いいから投げてよ。
Don't worry about it and just pitch.
ハァ…。
拾いに行くのは　椿だぞ。
You're gonna be the one picking them all up, you know?
I know.
（椿）分かってるよ！
有馬君と何かあった？
Did something happen between you and Arima?
（椿）うっ！　わあー！
（柏木）わあー！
（柏木）殺す気か！？　バカ椿！
Are you trying to take my head off, you idiot?!
（椿）あんたが
変なこと言うからでしょ！
It's your fault for saying something weird like that!
（柏木）ハッ　バレバレなんだ。
音楽室　狙って　打ち込んで…。
It's so obvious. You were clearly aiming for the music room.
またケンカしたの？
（椿）してない。
Did you two fight again?
Nope.
公生に
蹴り　ぶち込んでやっただけ。
I just gave Kousei a good kick.
Come to think of it, he was limping.
そういえば　足　引きずってたな。
He's an imbecile! A smartass! That Four Eyes!
唐変木！　ちょこざいな！
眼鏡！　もっと苦しめばいいんだ！
Suffer some more for all I care!
応援なんか
金輪際　行ってやるか！→
No way am I ever gonna show up to root for you again!
Live a lonely life!
孤独に生きろ！
Don't yell at me.
（柏木）《私に言われても…》
（椿）《もっと私のこと考えろ
バカ公生》→
Think about me more, Kousei, you idiot.
Reach him.
《届け　届け　私の打球》
My hit.
And you have no choice but to...
（椿）《あんたは　私と…》
《あれは　何だったのかな》
What was that all about, I wonder?
She was just messing around, right?
《単なる冗談だよね。
でも　椿が　あんな冗談…》
But if Tsubaki made that sort of joke...
（椿）《弟みたいなもんだよ》
He's like a kid brother.
What an enigma...
《謎だ。　女の子は謎だ》
Girls are just enigmas.
（紘子）ゴラー！
うっ　うわっ！
Seto
Hey, you!
（紘子）あんた　やる気あんの？
２月の本選まで　時間ないのよ！
Are you into this or not?
You don't have much time before the finals in February!
I'm sorry.
すみません。
（凪）お花畑な演奏ですね。　陳腐。
（小春）おねしょしたの？
What a cop-out of a performance.
How cliché.
Did he wet his pants?
（紘子）あんたは　努力と情熱を
備えた才能たちと戦うの。
You're up against some of the best who are full of grit and passion.
Whether you'll be going on to high
school here, or leaving the country,
（紘子）進学か　外へ出るか
このコンクール次第。
how you do in this competition
will decide your future as a pianist.
ピアニストとしての未来が
決まる。→
Keep yourself together.
しっかりしな。
あんたは岐路に立ってるのよ。
You're standing at the crossroads.
[TEL]もう　病院　来なくていいから。
You don't have to come to the hospital anymore.
えっ？
[TEL]もうすぐ　本選なんでしょ。→
Huh?
The final's coming up soon, right?
病院　来てる暇あるなら
譜面をさらう。→
If you have time to come here,
you should go over the sheet music.
Pound even one more measure into your head!
１小節でも　体にたたき込む！→
That's all! Bye-bye now!
そういうことだから
バイバイキーン。
何なんだよ！
What's up with that?! She's the one who told me to check in regularly!
自分が　定期連絡に来いって
言ったくせに！
She's so selfish, irresponsible, and outrageous!
わがまま！　無責任！　傍若無人！
《僕　何かしたかな》
Was it something I did?
《病室で　チョコ食べたのが
まずかったかな》
Maybe I shouldn't have eaten that chocolate bar at the hospital.
《お見舞いに行っても
黙ってるからかな》
And I don't say anything when I'm there.
《相座さんの話　したのが
よくなかったかな》
Maybe I shouldn't have talked about Aiza.
《定期連絡がなくなったら→
If I stop with these checks,
君に会いに行く理由が
なくなっちゃう》
then I won't have a reason to see you anymore.
[TEL]
何じゃい！
Incoming Call
Miyazono Kaori
What do you want?!
見て　見て。　飛行機が飛んでる。
夜間飛行だ。
Look! There's a plane in the sky!
It's a night flight!
[TEL]すごーい。
Amazing!
Huh?
えっ？　あっ…。　ああ　そうだね。
Hey, you're right.
[TEL]あれ？　君も見えるの？
へ～　空はつながってるんだね。
What? You can see it too?
Wow, we're really connected under one sky, aren't we?
えっ…　それだけ？
[TEL]うん。　いけない？
Oh, is that all?
Yes. Is that a problem?
《星の海を　飛行機が渡っていく》
The plane crosses the sea of stars.
《君は猫のよう。
音もなく近づき…》
Like a cat, you silently creep up to me.
病院に来るなって言った。
You told me not to come to the hospital.
But I didn't say I wouldn't call you.
[TEL]電話しないなんて
言ってないよ。→
低空だよ。　夜なのに。
It's flying really low, even though it's night.
She bombards me from an unexpected angle.
《予想のつかない角度から
翻弄する》
《僕は　あっけにとられて
いつも君のペース》
I'm dumbfounded, always following you.
I'll stop by again.
また　病院に行くよ。
だから　いいってば。
I told you, you don't have to.
君に　そんな暇ないでしょ。
You know you don't have the time.
暇とかじゃないよ。
It's not about the time.
君に会いたいんだ。
I want to see you.
《鉄の塊が　流れ星のよう》
A lump of metal, like a shooting star.
《君と同じ空を見ているだけで
見慣れた風景が違って見える》
Just seeing the same sky as you makes the familiar scenery look different.
《君のちょっとしたしぐさに
一喜一憂》
I swing between hope and despair at your slightest gesture,
《僕の心は
メロディーを奏でだす》
and my heart starts to play a melody.
There's a name for what I'm feeling,
but I can't quite put my finger on it.
《こういう感情を
何て呼んだかな》
《こういう　気持ちを
何ていったかな》
How do you describe this kind of thing in words?
《これは　たぶん　恋と呼ぶんだ》
I think it's probably...
called love.
いけない？
Is that a problem?
《これは　きっと
恋っていうんだ》
I'm sure this is what they call love.
Medication Room
（渡）やっと　決まったよ。
おっ　やったね。
I'm finally set.
Hey, good for you!
（渡）スポーツ推薦だから
決まって当然だけどな。→
Well, it's a sports scholarship, so no surprises there.
３月から　サッカー部に
顔　出せってさ。→
They told me to report to the soccer team starting in March.
また　下っ端に逆戻りだ。
きついぜ。→
It's the bottom of the heap all over again.
Gonna be tough.
にしても　珍しいな。→
Though, I'm surprised.
お見舞いに誘われるの
嫌がってたのに。
I thought you disliked coming with me to see her.
避けてたんだ。
I was just putting it off.
《僕は　いつも　渡と自分を比べて
落ち込んでしまう》
Whenever I compare myself to Watari, my heart sinks.
（椿）《公生は
かをちゃんが好きなんだよ》
You like Kao, Kousei.
《君は　君だよ》
You're you.
ねえ　渡。
Hey, Watari.
I really like Miyazono.
僕は　宮園さんが　とても好きだよ。
バカ。　知ってるよ。
You idiot.
I knew that.
Yeah.
Medication Room
（渡）ハハッ　やっと
俺と　やり合う気になったか！
So you're finally gonna duke it out with me, huh?
Medication Room
（看護師）片桐先生　呼んで！
Get Dr. Katagiri!
Medication Room
かをりちゃんの部屋じゃね？
Isn't that Kaori's room?
Medication Room
（看護師）しっかり！
すぐ　先生　来るからね！→
Hang on! The doctor will be here soon, all right?
Medication Room
宮園さん　分かる？
（看護師）すぐ元気になるからね。
Ms. Miyazono, are you with me?
You'll get better in no time, okay?
（看護師）宮園さん　深呼吸して！
（看護師）先生　急いでください！
Take a deep breath, Ms. Miyazono!
Please hurry, Doctor!
（看護師）宮園さん　宮園さん！→
Ms. Miyazono! Ms. Miyazono!
宮園さん　こっち見て！
宮園さん！→
Ms. Miyazono, look at me!
Ms. Miyazono!
宮園さん　こっち見て！
宮園さん　聞こえる？
Ms. Miyazono, look at me!
Ms. Miyazono, can you hear me?!
（看護師）宮園さん！
（看護師）あんたたち何してんの！
Ms. Miyazono!
What are you two doing?!
Ms. Miyazono! Stay with us!
We're treating her now!
（看護師）今　処置中なの。
今日は帰りなさい！
Go home today!
Hello?! Hello?! Hello?!
すみません！　すみません！
すみません！
（医師）レントゲン急いで。
血液型　調べて。
Get me that X-ray.
Check its blood type.
ひかれた時点で
ほとんど手遅れだったんだ。
He was pretty much beyond saving after he got hit.
残念だけど　だから…。
ありがとうございました。
I'm sorry,
but...
Thank you very much.
Are you okay?
大丈夫かい？
はい。
Yes.
《君は　忘れられるの？》
Do you really think you can forget?
《君も　行こう》
Come with us.
《私に触れて　喜んでる》
Your hands are happy just to be touching mine.
《君で　よかった》
I'm really glad it's you.
Episode 20
Hand in Hand
Episode 21
Snow
sore zore no yume wo erande
No two dreams can be the same
Episode 21
Snow
sore zore no yume wo erande
No two dreams can be the same
Watch next week too!